ootpdevelopments.com 2019-07-28

# Data Protection and Privacy Statement - Out of the Park Developments

[Open original version of the Data Protection and Privacy Statement in German language](https://www.ootpdevelopments.com/datenschutzerklaerung/)

###### **Name and address of the person responsible**

The person responsible within the meaning of the basic data protection regulation and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection regulations is the:

Out of the Park Development GmbH & Co KG  
Vorderstr. 44a  
21723 Hollern-Twielenfleth

Reported at the district court Tostedt HRA 100876

Tel .: 04141 792021  
Email: webmaster@ootpdevelopments.com  
Website: [http://www.ootpdevelopments.com](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://www.ootpdevelopments.com/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhj-mner5j5Oi4khRXVGFhnmzwfElg)

###### **2\. (Not applicable)**

###### **3.** **General information about data processing**

###### **1\. Scope of processing of personal data**

In principle, we process personal data of our users only insofar as this is necessary to provide a functioning website and our content and services. The processing of personal data of our users takes place regularly only with the consent of the user. An exception applies to cases in which prior consent can not be obtained for reasons of fact and the processing of the data is permitted by law.

**2\. Legal basis for the processing of personal data**

Insofar as we obtain the consent of the data subject for processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as legal basis.

In the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is a party, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO as legal basis. This also applies to processing operations required to carry out pre-contractual actions.

Insofar as processing of personal data is required to fulfill a legal obligation that is subject to our company, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c DSGVO as legal basis.

In the event that vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. d DSGVO as legal basis.

If processing is necessary to safeguard the legitimate interests of our company or a third party, and if the interests, fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject do not prevail over the first interest, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO as legal basis for processing.

**3\. Data deletion and storage duration**

The personal data of the data subject will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of the storage is deleted. In addition, such storage may be provided for by the European or national legislator in EU regulations, laws or other regulations to which the controller is subject. Blocking or deletion of the data also takes place when a storage period prescribed by the standards mentioned expires, unless there is a need for further storage of the data for conclusion of a contract or fulfillment of the contract.

###### **4\. Provision of the website and creation of logfiles**

**1\. Description and scope of data processing**

Each time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects data and information from the computer system of the calling computer.

The following data is collected here:

_(1) Information about the browser type and version used_

_(2) The operating system of the user_

_(3) The Internet service provider of the user_

_(4) The IP address of the user_

_(5) Date and time of access_

_(6) Websites from which the system of the user comes to our website_

_(7) Web sites accessed by the user’s system through our website_

The data is also stored in the log files of our system. A storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.

**2\. Legal basis for data processing**

The legal basis for the temporary storage of data and log files is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

**3\. Purpose of the data processing**

The temporary storage of the IP address by the system is necessary to allow delivery of the website to the computer of the user. To do this, the user’s IP address must be kept for the duration of the session.

Storage in log files is done to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, the data is used to optimize the website and to ensure the security of our information technology systems. An evaluation of the data for marketing purposes does not take place in this context.

For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

**4\. Duration of storage**

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. In the case of collecting the data for providing the website, this is the case when the respective session is completed.

In the case of storing the data in log files, this is the case after no more than seven days. An additional storage is possible. In this case, the IP addresses of the users are deleted or alienated, so that an assignment of the calling client is no longer possible.

**5\. Opposition and removal possibility**

The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of the data in log files is essential for the operation of the website. There is consequently no contradiction on the part of the user.

###### **5\. Use of cookies**

**1\. a) Description and scope of data processing**

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in the Internet browser or the Internet browser on the user’s computer system. When a user visits a website, a cookie may be stored on the user’s operating system. This cookie contains a characteristic string that allows the browser to be uniquely identified when the website is reopened.

We use cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some elements of our website require that the calling browser be identified even after a page break.

The following data is stored and transmitted in the cookies:

_(1) language settings_

_(2) log-in information_

In addition, we use cookies on our website that allow an analysis of users’ browsing behavior.

In this way, the following data can be transmitted:

_(1) Entered search terms_

_(2) frequency of page views_

_(3) Use of Website Features_

The data of the users collected in this way are pseudonymized by technical precautions. Therefore, an assignment of the data to the calling user is no longer possible. The data will not be stored together with other personal data of the users.

When accessing our website, users are informed by an information banner about the use of cookies for analysis purposes and referred to this privacy policy. In this context, there is also an indication of how the storage of cookies in the browser settings can be prevented.

**1\. b) Legal basis for data processing**

The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO.

**1\. c) Purpose of the data processing**

The purpose of using technically necessary cookies is to facilitate the use of websites for users. Some features of our website can not be offered without the use of cookies. For these, it is necessary that the browser is recognized even after a page break.

We require cookies for the following applications:

_(1) adoption of language settings_

_(2) Remember keywords_

The user data collected through technically necessary cookies will not be used to create user profiles.

The use of the analysis cookies is for the purpose of improving the quality of our website and its contents. Through the analysis cookies, we learn how the website is used and so we can constantly optimize our offer.

For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of personal data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

**1\. d) Duration of storage, objection and removal possibility**

Cookies are stored on the computer of the user and transmitted by this on our side. Therefore, as a user, you have full control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can disable or restrict the transmission of cookies. Already saved cookies can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. If cookies are disabled for our website, it may not be possible to use all the functions of the website to the full.

###### **6\. Newsletter **

**1\. Description and scope of data processing**

The newsletter is sent based on the user’s registration on the website:

On our website you can subscribe to a free newsletter. When registering for the newsletter, the email address from the input mask will be sent to us.

In addition, the following data is collected upon registration:

_(1) IP address of the calling computer_

_(2) Date and time of registration_

For the processing of the data, your consent is obtained during the registration process and reference is made to this privacy policy.

If you purchase goods or services on our website and deposit your e-mail address here, this can subsequently be used by us to send a newsletter. In such a case, the newsletter will only send direct mail for your own similar goods or services.

In connection with the processing of data for the sending of newsletters, there is no disclosure of the data to third parties. The data will be used exclusively for sending the newsletter.

**2\. Legal basis for data processing**

The legal basis for the processing of the data after the user has registered for the newsletter is the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

The legal basis for sending the newsletter as a result of the sale of goods or services is § 7 Abs. 3 UWG.

**3\. Purpose of the data processing**

The collection of the user’s e-mail address serves to deliver the newsletter.

The collection of other personal data in the context of the registration process serves to prevent misuse of the services or the email address used.

**4\. Duration of storage**

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. The e-mail address of the user is therefore stored as long as the subscription to the newsletter is active.

The other personal data collected during the registration process will normally be deleted after a period of seven days.

**5\. Opposition and removal possibility**

Subscription to the newsletter may be terminated at any time by the user concerned. For this purpose, there is a corresponding link in each newsletter.

This also allows a revocation of the consent to the storage of the personal data collected during the registration process.

###### **7\. Registration**

**1\. Description and scope of data processing**

On our website, we offer users the opportunity to register by providing personal information. The data is entered into an input mask and transmitted to us and stored. A transfer of data to third parties does not take place. As part of the registration process, the email address, username and profile settings are saved as they are entered. At the time of registration, the following data is also stored:

_(1) The IP address of the user_

_(2) Date and time of registration_

As part of the registration process, the consent of the user to process this data is obtained.

**2\. Legal basis for data processing**

Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

If the registration serves the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party or the implementation of pre-contractual measures, an additional legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.

**3\. Purpose of the data processing**

User registration is required for the provision of certain content and services on our website, in particular for posting content on our message board and for using Challenge Mode. A registration of the user is necessary to fulfill a contract with the user or to carry out pre-contractual measures, eg when using the webstore.

**4\. Duration of storage**

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.

This is the case for the data collected during the registration process when the registration on our website is canceled or modified.

This is the case during the registration process for the performance of a contract or for the performance of pre-contractual measures if the data are no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contracting party in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations.

**5\. Opposition and removal possibility**

As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Please contact us by email at info@ootpdevelopments.com

If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.

###### **8\. Contact form and e-mail contact**

**1\. Description and scope of data processing**

On our website is a contact form available, which can be used for electronic contact. If a user realizes this option, the data entered in the input mask, such as the email address, name and product information, will be transmitted to us and saved.

_(1) The IP address of the user_

_(2) Date and time of registration_

For the processing of the data in the context of the sending process your consent is obtained and referred to this privacy statement.

Alternatively, contact via the provided e-mail address is possible. In this case, the user’s personal data transmitted by e-mail will be stored.

In this context, there is no disclosure of the data to third parties. The data is used exclusively for processing the conversation.

**2\. Legal basis for data processing**

Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

The legal basis for the processing of the data transmitted in the course of sending an e-mail is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. If the e-mail contact aims to conclude a contract, then additional legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.

**3\. Purpose of the data processing**

The processing of the personal data from the input mask serves us only to process the contact. In the case of contact via e-mail, this also includes the required legitimate interest in the processing of the data.

The other personal data processed during the sending process serve to prevent misuse of the contact form and to ensure the security of our information technology systems.

**4\. Duration of storage**

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. For the personal data from the input form of the contact form and those sent by e-mail, this is the case when the respective conversation with the user has ended. The conversation is ended when it can be inferred from the circumstances that the relevant facts have been finally clarified.

The additional personal data collected during the sending process will be deleted at the latest after a period of seven days.

**5\. Opposition and removal possibility**

The user has the possibility at any time to revoke his consent to the processing of the personal data. If the user contacts us by e-mail, he may object to the storage of his personal data at any time. In such a case, the conversation can not continue.

The revocation of the consent and the objection of storage must be addressed to the above-mentioned email address or postal address.

All personal data stored in the course of contacting will be deleted in this case.

###### **9\. web analytics **

**1\. Scope of processing of personal data**

On our website we use tools to analyze the surfing behavior of our users. The software sets a cookie on the computer of the users (for cookies see above). If individual pages of our website are called, the following data is stored:

_(1) IP address of the calling system of the user_

_(2) The called website_

_(3) The website from which the user came to the accessed website (referrer)_

_(4) The subpages that are called from the called web page_

_(5) The length of stay on the website_

_(6) The frequency of calling the website_

The software runs exclusively on the servers of our website. A storage of the personal data of the users takes place only there. A transfer of the data to third parties does not take place.

**2\. The legal basis for the processing of personal data**

The legal basis for processing users’ personal data is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO.

**3\. Purpose of the data processing**

The processing of users’ personal data enables us to analyze the surfing behavior of our users. By analyzing the obtained data, we are able to compile information about the use of the individual components of our website. This helps us to constantly improve our website and its user-friendliness. For these purposes, our legitimate interest lies in the processing of the data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The anonymisation of the IP address sufficiently takes into account the interest of users in their protection of personal data.

**4\. Duration of storage**

The data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer needed for our recording purposes.

**5\. Opposition and removal possibility**

Cookies are stored on the computer of the user and transmitted by this to our site. Therefore, as a user, you have full control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can disable or restrict the transmission of cookies. Already saved cookies can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. If cookies are disabled for our website, it may not be possible to use all the functions of the website to the full.

**6\. Google Analytics**

On the basis of our legitimate interests (ie interest in the analysis, optimization of the association’s activities and the economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. [6](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://dejure.org/gesetze/DSGVO/6.html&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhj5UsYb55kB26QIorfgqx6wMYOCoQ) (1) lit. DSGVO), we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). ) on. Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the online offer by the users are usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ( [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant%3Fid%3Da2zt000000001L5AAI%26status%3DActive&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhiM5TG5NWPZTkiyAuASdCzQI6ad_w) ).

Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our online offer by users, to compile reports on the activities within this online offer and to provide us with further services related to the use of this online offer and the internet usage. In this case, pseudonymous usage profiles of the users can be created from the processed data.

We only use Google Analytics with activated IP anonymization. This means that the IP address of the users will be shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there.

The IP address submitted by the user’s browser will not be merged with other data provided by Google. Users can prevent the storage of cookies by setting their browser software accordingly; Users may also prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to its use of the online offer and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: [http: // tools .google.com / dlpage / gaoptout? hl = DE](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout%3Fhl%3Dde&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhiMl6MaXpQ6b46etbC6lVF8fmxlIw) .

For more information about Google’s data usage, hiring and opt-out options, please visit Google’s websites: [https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/partners&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhg42k9Y8uB_ViwBZgdGXGjLw3wENg) (“Google’s use of your data when you use websites or apps our partners “), [http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhhnqCVQc_eSU37QAA7N4SdRcPfm7A) (” Use of data for promotional purposes “), [http://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://www.google.de/settings/ads&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhikusZEx4EWyv4AhsfQsn9B-fAaKQ) (” Managing information that Google uses, to show you advertising “).

###### **10\. Integration of services and content of third parties**

Based on our legitimate interests (ie interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. [6](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://dejure.org/gesetze/DSGVO/6.html&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhj5UsYb55kB26QIorfgqx6wMYOCoQ) (1) lit. DSGVO), we make use of content or services offered by third-party providers in order to provide their content and services Services, such as images, videos or fonts (hereinafter collectively referred to as “Content”).

This always presupposes that the third-party providers of this content perceive the IP address of the users, since they could not send the content to their browser without the IP address. The IP address is therefore required for the presentation of this content. We endeavor to use only content whose respective providers use the IP address solely for the delivery of the content. Third parties may also use so-called pixel tags (invisible graphics, also referred to as “web beacons”) for statistical or marketing purposes. The “pixel tags” can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website. The pseudonymous information may also be stored in cookies on the user’s device and may include, but is not limited to, technical information about the browser and operating system, referring web sites, visit time, and other information regarding the use of our online offer.

**Youtube**

We embed the videos on the YouTube platform of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Privacy Policy: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhiQzHMQj3Eoy4p5HxuiNri765dLtQ) , opt-out: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhiV3RILXA3GpQu6s1MyzFzh9xH1yA) .

**Google Maps**

We include maps from the Google Maps service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Privacy Policy: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhiQzHMQj3Eoy4p5HxuiNri765dLtQ) , opt-out: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhiV3RILXA3GpQu6s1MyzFzh9xH1yA) .

**Use of Facebook social plugins**

On the basis of our legitimate interests (ie interest in the analysis, optimization of the economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. [6](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://dejure.org/gesetze/DSGVO/6.html&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhj5UsYb55kB26QIorfgqx6wMYOCoQ) (1) lit. DSGVO) we use social plugins (“plugins”) of the social network facebook.com, which is operated by Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”). The plugins can represent interaction elements or content (eg videos, graphics or text contributions) and can be recognized by one of the Facebook logos (white “f” on blue tile, the terms “Like”, “Like” or a “thumbs up” sign ) or are marked with the addition “Facebook Social Plugin”. The list and appearance of Facebook Social Plugins can be viewed here: [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhhLCtrKSFSoubtINaFTI8b3vK1UhQ) .

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ( [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant%3Fid%3Da2zt0000000GnywAAC%26status%3DActive&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhj7vu3qZpo2_MyPufWUwyxsQKJ0TQ) ).

When a user invokes a feature of this online offering that includes such a plugin, their device establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plugin is transmitted by Facebook directly to the device of the user and incorporated by him into the online offer. In the process, user profiles can be created from the processed data. We therefore have no influence on the amount of data that Facebook collects with the help of this plugin and therefore informs the users according to our knowledge.

By integrating the plugins, Facebook receives the information that a user has accessed the corresponding page of the online offer. If the user is logged in to Facebook, Facebook can assign the visit to his Facebook account. If users interact with the plugins, for example, press the Like button or leave a comment, the information is transmitted from your device directly to Facebook and stored there. If a user is not a member of Facebook, there is still the possibility that Facebook will find out and save their IP address. According to Facebook, only an anonymous IP address is stored in Germany.

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook, as well as the related rights and setting options for protecting the privacy of users, can be found in Facebook’s privacy policy: [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhisilUl5mKpQepstV3CTFwucSsHsw) ,

If a user is a Facebook member and does not want Facebook to collect data about him via this online offer and link it to his member data stored on Facebook, he must log out of Facebook and delete his cookies before using our online offer. Other settings and inconsistencies regarding the use of data for advertising purposes are possible within the Facebook profile settings: [https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.facebook.com/settings%3Ftab%3Dads&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhgPKzxeQZYbhvafbJ-lKo69VFg6kA) or via the US-American site [http://www.aboutads.info / choices /](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://www.aboutads.info/choices/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhj6aqS46kiAKVhTUQQmijyVb9PHKA) or the EU page [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://www.youronlinechoices.com/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhgSESQmHXtnKHLGSXe671rjvUWLHg) . The settings are platform-independent, ie they are adopted for all devices, such as desktop computers or mobile devices.

**Twitter**

Within our online offering, features and content of the Twitter service may be incorporated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. This may include, for example, content such as images, videos or text and buttons, with which users can announce their favor regarding the content, the authors of the content or our contributions can subscribe. If the users are members of the platform Twitter, Twitter can assign the call of the above mentioned contents and functions to the profiles of the users. Privacy Statement from Twitter: [https://twitter.com/privacy](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://twitter.com/de/privacy&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhgSpZ4ssCKglfSQU8BVVCG9-ZorwQ) . Twitter is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ( [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant%3Fid%3Da2zt0000000TORzAAO%26status%3DActive&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhjunK2xhS_XcgKRBWjqPZJ5JeHW-g) ). Privacy Policy: https://twitter.com/privacy, Opt-Out: [https://twitter.com/personalization](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=https://twitter.com/personalization&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhhYMSRq8ffJ8hcVgkaPYpL9g_UAig) .

**Instagram**

Within our online offering may include functions and content of the service Instagram, offered by the Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA. This may include, for example, content such as images, videos or text and buttons, with which users can tell their favor regarding the content, the authors of the content or our contributions can subscribe. If the users are members of the platform Instagram, Instagram can assign the call of the above mentioned contents and functions to the profiles of the users there. Instagram privacy policy: [http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://translate.googleusercontent.com/translate_c?depth=1&hl=de&rurl=translate.google.com&sl=de&sp=nmt4&tl=en&u=http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/&xid=17259,15700023,15700124,15700149,15700168,15700173,15700186,15700191,15700201,15700205&usg=ALkJrhjRKkE7JW5zs4qodSY-PuYiNVZYzw) .

**Links to other websites**

Our online offer contains links to other websites. We have no control over their operators adhering to the privacy policy.  
We are responsible as a provider of own content according to the general laws. Of these own contents may be to distinguish links to the contents held by other providers content. We do not accept any responsibility for third-party content which is provided via links to use and which are specially marked, and we do not adopt their content as our own. For illegal, incorrect or incomplete contents as well as for damage resulting from the use or non-use of the information, the provider of the website, which was referred to, is liable. The editorial office is only responsible for third-party information if it has a positive knowledge of them, that is also of any illegal or punishable content, and if it is technically possible and reasonable to prevent their use.

In this context, we refer to the judgment of the LG Hamburg of 12.05.1998, in the position on “Liability for link references to homepage pages” was taken. The verdict states that one has to take responsibility for the contents of the linked page by attaching link references on the own homepage sides to strange homepage sides if necessary. According to the district court, this can only be prevented by expressly distancing oneself from these contents (Landgericht Hamburg – 312 O 85/98).  
We hereby expressly distance ourselves from all contents of all linked pages on our homepage.

This statement applies to all links on our homepage or in the social media of SV HTw.  
All trademarks mentioned in the text on this website or in the social media of SV HTw are registered trademarks of their respective manufacturers.
